## JOSEPH CORBIN

123 Bndge Street, Boston, MA 12345 youremail@example com (123) 4-56-7890

Dedicated and resourceful Occupational Therapist with 10+ years of advancement and experience at major hospital facilities.

Demonstrated excellence in helping patients chart a return to daily life following recovery from illness, injury, or major surgery, Draw consistent praise from colleagues and managers For quickly assessing challenges and finding new ways to optimize palient outcomes.

Make highly informed care recommendations based on a dose review of each patient's health status, priorities, and home or work environment. Natural coach and mentor. Recently helped devise new OT training measures and principles adopted by other hospital disciplines. Augment OT expertise with a firm commitment to efficiency, collaboration, and process improvement.

#### **EDUCATION**

MASTER OF SCIENCE (MS) - OCCUPATIONAL THERAPY

Boston College, Boston, MA January 2008 - January 2012

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE (BS) - PSYCHOLOGY

Harvard University, Cambridge, MA January 2004 - January 2008

### **KEY SKILLS**

- Coaching & Mentoring
- Durable Medical Equipment (DME)
- Home & Workplace Evaluation
- ♦ Hospital Discharge Planning
- · Large-Scale Hospital Operations
- Operational Streamlining
- Patient & Family Relations
- · Patient Consult & Assessment
- Process Redesign & Improvement
- Reporting & Documentation
- Task Prioritization
- Team Leadership & Collaboration
- Training Development
- · Treatment Planning

# CERTIFICATIONS & LICENSURES

- Certified, National Board of Certification of Occupational Therapy (NBCOT), 2012
- Occupational Therapy License,
   Massachusetts, 2012

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

OCCUPATIONAL THERAPIST
Massachusetts General Hospital,
Boston, MA
April 2018 to Present

- Create personalized OT treatment plans for diverse patients al this major regional hospital facility
- Assist patients with activities of daily living (ADLs) such as bathing, dressing, and food preparation to support recovery and gauge readiness for discharge from hospital
- Coordinate with physical therapist to help determine and recommend next phase of each patient's recovery, drawing on broad knowledge of available rehab, home health, and other services
- Contribute ideas and strategies to streamline operations further, standardize policies, and advance team success
- Highlight: Co-developed training modules that helped enhance onboarding and performance of newly hired OT assistants. Several other hospital departments adopted successful new training approaches and systems

OCCUPATIONAL THERAPIST Boston Medical Center, Boston, MA January 2012 to April 2018

- Supported patients in carrying out ADLs io facilitate recovery and discharge planning at this large healthcare facility.
- Consulted with patients to help set clear, attainable goals for regaining mobility and resuming daily work, life, and social activities
- Provided a detailed update after patient consults to ensure nurses' full awareness of progress and any ongoing concerns
- Demonstrated early leadership overseeing and motivating three OT assistants Gained appreciation for coaching as the primary means to tap employee talents and drive team success